hello everyone this is Frank defreitis
welcome to another week of how we'll
talk for the week of April 26th
1999 and this is a special week here on
holotalk
and just for the whole talk listeners I
will be giving a web page so that you
can go to the page itself and see the
results of the tests using the 35
milliwatt laser diode module and folks I
just want to announce right now that it
worked way beyond my expectations
I didn't have a lot of time to work on
it this week so the shot that I did I
actually combined a few different
elements in order to get a few different
results into one shot in fact the laser
itself looks so good
that I just felt comfortable going ahead
and doing it and what I did isn't I shot
a piece of four by five inch film but
the reason why this test was so
important was because you could do some
pretty large format Holograms using a 35
milliwatt light source uh helium neon
continuous Wave light source and I was
hoping that this module would show some
promise in allowing us to do the same
thing
inexpensively
as far as I can tell the cheapest I
could find this the diode itself was 33
on the web for this 35 milliwatt diode
and it's at 658 nanometers and when you
take into consideration that the driver
is going to cost another 30 the
collimating lens is going to cost you
another 20 or 30 in the barrel another
20.
you're looking at just over a little
over one hundred dollars to put this 35
milliwatt diode module together compared
to many thousands of dollars for
purchasing a new 30 five milliwatt
helium neon laser getting the same
performance so it's it was an incredible
test that I was hoping with all my heart
would work and when I got the module
finally set up and we powered this baby
up it looks so so beautiful now I had a
few options put into it such as
anamorphic prisons
circularized beam and
I don't think that's absolutely
necessary but I want to do experiment
with that a little bit and you'll see
the photos of all this and the results
so once again I shot the piece of Carl I
don't know if you're getting sick of the
piece of car all the time every time you
log onto the page but I shoot this piece
of Carl because I can compare it to the
other shots that have been made with all
the different diodes
so once again I shot the call but the
difference this time was that I spread
the light out so that it would cover a
30 by 40 inch plate so in other words
the holographic setup was set up to
shoot a 30 by 40 centimeter I'm sorry I
think I may have said inches and I'm not
going to edit this at all because it's
almost 8 o'clock now and I've got to get
this up so I meant 30 by 40 centimeter
plate which is about 12 by 16 inches I
believe
that's what the system was set up to
shoot and then into that system I put
the four by five inch piece of film to
shoot the coil and I explained that
process on the page as well and you can
go to the web page here's the address
and the addresses well if you open your
browser up get your browser back in the
front in front of the real audio player
you'll see that the actual page that
you're on right now for holotalk is
www.homoworld.com
Holo slash
homotalk.html the only thing you need to
change is the whole talk dot HTML and
you want to change that to diode 14 dot
HTML
that's diode 14 d i o d e 14 dot HTML
and it will take you to the page that
has the report and all the photos
and later on in the week I haven't had
any time this weekend to do this
but later on the week I will be doing
some higher quality shots and a little
bit further on down the road actually
doing a 30 by 40 centimeter uh glass
plate hologram using this dial that I
don't have any 30 by 40 centimeter
plates in here but I do have one eight
by ten left and I will probably use that
eight by ten as well so it it was well
beyond my expectations I didn't really
know what to think would it work would
it not work it was a long shot anyone
who would say that you could get 35
milliwatts of power and get a nice
hologram out of something that's only
going to cost you a hundred and some
dollars that would be crazy just a few
months ago but here we are today and
it's uh it is now a reality so large
format and and when you get up into
around 30 by 40 centimeter plates that's
considered the I would imagine the lower
end of large format large format
holography is now within the reach of so
many people in fact hundred and some
dollars I know there's a couple catalogs
with used
five milliwatt laser heads plus the
power supplies that are going to cost
you over a hundred dollars and this is
35 milliwatts and the beam is beautiful
and probably due to the prisms you know
the green profile itself but it was so
beautifully spatial filtered onto the
white light oh it was it's it's hypnotic
658 nanometers is a beautiful beautiful
uh wavelength to work with it's uh it's
intoxicating it really is it's beautiful
and it didn't have that the wavelength
did not have that much of an adverse
effect on the final hologram now you
would think you're that far away from
633 that uh
you know you wouldn't get very nice
results from it but that's absolutely
not true at all I did not treat the film
with any triathanolamine or anything
like that I just I'm telling you I just
took that film sandwich between two
pieces of glass no index matching fluid
nothing I just wanted to see if it would
work and that's the shot that I have up
there for you so if that's how good it
gets
um working that quickly and without that
much pair imagine what it would do once
we sit down and we start to improve the
quality and actually do some very
beautiful work
so it's a short show this week I have to
actually take this I'm not going to edit
it but I still have to compress it with
real audio and then get it up to the web
upload it and
I want to thank you very much for tuning
in and this was special just for whole
talk listeners I do not have any links
to this page for anyone else except for
holo talk listeners for this week and
then next week I will make that page
available to everyone but I wanted all
the talk listeners to be the first ones
to be able to see this and read the
report and hopefully I really do hope
that a few of you decide to give this a
try because you know it even if you're
working with a 20 watt argon or higher
this is just so addicting to be able to
take one of these little tiny diode
modules and have that much intensity and
that much light come out of it that you
can just spread that beam out and and do
large Holograms with it it's just and
then have the Holograms turn out very
very nice it's uh it's just a just a
wonderful thing so thank you very much
for tuning in I'm going to head out and
enjoy the report send me an email if you
want to chat about it a little bit and
I'll talk to you next week take care